Hey, gorgeous. How's it going?
嘿 帅哥 最近怎么样啊
Dehydrated Japanese noodles under fluorescent lights.
在节能灯下吃脱水面条
Does it get better than this?
夫复何求啊
Question: You're not dating, are you?
你现在应该没有对象吧
I met somebody who would be perfect for you.
因为我这有个人 跟你是绝配
You see, perfect might be a problem.
说是绝配太草率了吧
Had you said co-dependent or self-destructive...
说互虐 或者自残比较好一点
-You want a date Saturday? -Yes, please.
-周六想约会吗  -必须的 拜托了
okay
好的
He is cute.
他帅气
-He's funny. He's... -He's a he?
-幽默..  -男的吗
Well, yeah.
是啊
Oh, God. I just...
我还以为...
You're nice... Oh, God.
我错了 天啊
Good, Shelly. Okay. I'm gonna go flush myself down the toilet now.
我去卫生间找个马桶钻进去好了
Okay. Bye-bye.
再见 先闪了
老·友·记
S01E08  The One Where Nana Dies Twice
第一季第八集  葬礼风波
■
字幕制作
Subtitled By
@张纳德nerd
■
讨论邮箱
Discuss
f6dicuss@163.com (或私信)
■
鸣谢
Special Thanks
Psychd(英文字幕)
It's hard to enjoy noodles after that.
我听完连面条都不想吃了
Is that ridiculous?
这也太扯了吧
Can you believe she actually thought that?
说出来估计你们都不信
Yeah.
信了
Well, when I first met you, I thought maybe...
我第一次见你的时候 我就有点...
...possibly...
怀疑...
...you might be.
你是不是...
You did?
你怀疑过
Then you spent Phoebe's birthday party talking to my breasts...
但之后你在菲比的生日上 一直对着我的胸说话
...so then I figured maybe not.
我就知道你不是了
Huh. Did, uh, any of the rest of you guys think that when you first met me?
你们呢 你们刚认识我的时候也这样吗
-I did. -I think so.
-我是  -我也是
-Not me. -No, no, me neither.
-我没有  -嗯 我也是
Although, uh, back in college, Susan Saladore did.
不过大学的时候 苏珊是这么认为的
You're kidding.
逗我呢吧
-Did you tell her I wasn't? -No.
-你告诉她我不是了吗  -没有
It's because I wanted to go out with her too.
我当时也想追她啊
So I told her, actually, you were seeing Bernie Spellman...
所以我告诉她 你正在和伯尼约会
...who also liked her.
因为伯尼也喜欢她
Well, this is fascinating.
这事有点意思啊
So, uh, what is it about me?
为什么你们会这么想呢
I don't know. Because you're smart, you're funny...
不知道 大概是你既聪明又幽默吧
Ross is smart and funny. You ever think that about him?
罗斯也是啊 你们怀疑过他吗
-Ha, ha. Yeah, right. -What is it?
-说的还真是呢  -到底是为啥啊
Okay, I don't know. You just... You have a quality.
我也说不上来 你就是有这种...气质
-Yes, exactly. -Right?
-说得对  -没错
Yeah, a quality.
气质
"A quality." Good.
噢 这样啊
I was worried you were gonna be vague about this.
我还担心你们会说的多抽象呢
Hello?
喂
Oh. Rachel. It's Paolo calling from Rome.
瑞秋 保罗从罗马打来的
Oh, my God. Calling from Rome.
噢耶 罗马打来的电话
So he's calling from Rome. I could do that.
不就在罗马打电话吗 我也行啊
Just gotta go to Rome.
去罗马就行了
Monica, your dad just beeped in. Can you make it quick?
莫妮卡 你爸打来的 能快点说吗
I'm talking to Rome.
我正和罗马通话呢
talking to Rome...
和罗马
Hey, Dad. What's up?
嘿 啥事啊老爸
Oh, God.
不会吧
Ross, it's Nana.
罗斯 姥姥出事了
So, uh, how's she doing?
姥姥怎么样了
The doctor says it's a matter of hours.
医生说只是时间问题了
-How are you, Mom?  -Me? I'm fine, fine.
-你呢 妈妈  -我没事 没事
I'm glad you're here.
有你来真是太好了
What's with your hair?
你头发怎么了
What?
啥
What's different?
和以前不一样了吧
Nothing.
没有啊
Oh, maybe that's it.
噢 也许就是这个问题
She's unbelievable. Her mother's...
太扯了吧 她妈妈还在里面...
Okay, relax, relax.
淡定 放松
We are gonna be here a while, it looks like.
看起来我们得待一会儿了
We still have boyfriends and your career to cover.
所以还得聊你的感情和事业呢
Oh, God.
我靠
The fuzzy little mints at the bottom of her purse.
在她挎包底层 还有一块长毛的薄荷糖
Yeah, they were gross.
没错 恶心死了
Oh, you know what I love?
你知道我最喜欢什么吗
Her Sweet 'N Lows.
姥姥的人工袋糖
How she was always stealing them from restaurants.
她总是从餐馆偷偷的带回来
Not just restaurants, from our house.
不只从餐馆 从咱家也没少拿
Mrs. Geller?
盖勒夫人
She looks so small.
她看起来可真小
I know.
是啊
Well, at least she's with Pop-Pop and Aunt Phyllis now.
至少她又能见到姥爷和舅妈了
Goodbye, Nana.
再见了 姥姥
Bye, Nana.
再见了
Ross!
快走啊
Nurse.
医生
What is going on?
发生什么了
You know, uh, how the nurse said Nana had passed?
刚才不是说姥姥已经走了吗
Well, she's not quite.
不过貌似没走太远
-What? -She's not passed.
-啥  -姥姥还没死呢
She's present. She's back.
她又回来了
What's going on?
发生什么了
She may have died.
她可能已经去世了
"She may have died"?
可能去世了
We're looking into it.
我们正在深入的调查
Uh, I'll go see.
我进去看看
This almost never happens.
从来没发生过这种事
Now she's passed.
现在她走远了
I just have to know, okay?
我今天必须要搞清楚
Is it my hair?
是因为我的发型吗
Yes, Chandler, that's exactly what it is. It's your hair.
没错 钱德 就是因为你的发型
Yeah, you have homosexual hair.
对 你理的是同性恋标准型
So did she?
这么说 你姥姥...
Twice.
两次
Oh, that sucks.
噢 太槽糕了
You guys okay?
你俩没事吧
I don't know. It's weird.
不知道 感觉很怪
I know she's gone, but I just don't feel, uh...
她确实去世了 但是我总感觉...
Maybe that's because she's not really gone.
或许是因为她还没离开你们
No, no, she's gone.
肯定离开了
We checked.
我们检查过了
A lot.
查了很多遍
No, I mean, maybe no one ever really goes.
我的意思是 也许所有人都不曾离开过
Ever since my mom died, every now and then...
自从我妈妈死后 我总是经常的...
...I get this feeling that she's, like, right here, you know?
感觉她就在这里 你知道吗
Oh. And Debbie, my best friend from junior high...
还有黛比 我初中时候的死党
...got struck by lightning on a miniature golf course.
在迷你高尔夫球场被闪电劈死了
I always get this strong Debbie vibe...
现在每当我用那种黄色的小铅笔时
...whenever I use one of those little yellow pencils.
我就能感觉到她的气息
I miss her.
我想她了
Aw. Here, Pheebs.
给你这个 菲比
Want this?
这个行吗
-Oh, thanks. -Sure.
-太谢谢你了  -不用
I just sharpened her this morning.
我今早才削的
See, I don't believe any of that. I think when you're dead...
我就不太信这些东西 我认为一旦你咽气了
...you're dead. You're gone. You're worm food.
你就离开这里了 变成虫子们的食物了
So Chandler looks gay, huh?
钱德像同性恋来着是吧
I don't know who this is, but it's not Debbie.
我不知道这是谁 但肯定不是黛比
I thought it'd be a closed casket.
不是会放在棺材里面么
Well, that doesn't mean she can't look nice.
那也得打扮一下啊
Sweetie, you think you can get in there?
你看你能翻过去吗
I don't see why not.
应该可以
Here's my retainer.
我的矫牙器
I was just thinking...
我这两天一直在想
-...when my time comes... -Dad.
-等我死了之后  -别瞎说
Listen to me.
听我说完
When my time comes, I wanna be buried at sea.
我死了之后 我希望能被葬在海里
You what?
你说啥
I wanna be buried at sea. It looks like fun.
海葬 听起来挺好玩的
Define "fun."
哪好玩了
Come on. You'll make a day of it. You'll get a boat, pack a lunch...
你们可以快乐一整天啊  驾着小船 装着午餐
And then we throw your body in the water.
然后把你扔到海里
Gee, that does sound fun.
听起来确实好玩
Everyone thinks they know me.
大家都以为他们了解我
Everyone says, "Jack Geller, so predictable."
他们都说 '杰克·盖勒 循规蹈矩的人'
Maybe after I'm gone, they'll say, "Buried at sea? Huh."
没准等我死了 他们就会说'哈 海葬啊'
That's probably what they'll say.
他们确实可能会那么说
I'd like that.
我还挺喜欢的
-Hey, gorgeous. -Hey.
-嘿 美女  -嘿
Look, I'm sorry about yesterday.
昨天的事我十分抱歉
Don't worry about it. Apparently, other people have made the same mistake.
没关系 显然其他人也是这么看我的
Oh. Okay. Phew.
噢 那我就放心了
So, uh, what do you think it is about me?
你是根据什么来判断的呢
I don't know what.
我也说不上来
You just have...
你就是有一种...
...a quality. -A quality. Right. Great.
气质  -气质 说的好
It's a shame, because you and Lowell would've made a great couple.
太可惜了 你跟洛尔看起来特般配
Lowell? Financial Services Lowell? That's who you saw me with?
金融部的洛尔 你打算给我俩牵线来着吗
What? He's cute.
咋了 他挺帅的啊
Well, yeah.
没错
He's no Brian in Payroll.
但还是比不上工资部的布莱恩
Is Brian?
难道布莱恩也是...
No. I don't know. The point is, if you were gonna set me up...
我也不知道 我的意思是如果你要给我牵线的话
...I'd like to think it'd be with somebody like him.
至少也要布莱恩那种水准的吧
Well, I think Brian's a little out of your league.
我觉得他有点超出你的范围了
Excuse me. You don't think I could get a Brian?
你觉得我配不上布莱恩吗
Because I could get a Brian. Believe you me.
我分分钟就能搞定布莱恩 相信我
I'm really not.
好吧 我不能
This one?
这件呢
No.
不行
I've shown you every dress we have.
所有的衣服都在这了
Unless you want her to spend eternity in a lemon-yellow pantsuit...
除非你们想让她穿柠檬黄长裤
...go with the burgundy.
配紫红色衣服
Whatever we pick, she would've told us it's the wrong one.
不管我们选什么 她都不会满意的
You're right. We'll go with the burgundy.
没错 就选紫红的那件了
A fine choice. I'm coming out.
选的不赖 我要出来了
Wait. We need shoes.
等会 还没选鞋呢
Okay. Uh...
好的
How about these?
这双咋样
That's really a day shoe.
那是白天穿的鞋子吧
And where she's going, everyone else will be dressier?
她去的地方还挺讲究的是吗
Could we see something in a slimmer heel?
看看有细跟的鞋吗
Okay. I have nothing in an evening shoe in the burgundy.
没有紫红色的正式鞋
I can show you something in a silver that may work.
倒是有双银色的能凑合用吗
No, it really should be burgundy.
不行 必须用紫红色的
-Unless we go with a different dress. -Yes.
-要不换条裙子吧  -好主意
No, no, no. Watch this.
打住 稍等一下
Wait, I may have something in the back.
等会儿 我在找找看
Oh, my God.
天啊
Is everything all right, dear?
怎么了 亲爱的
Yeah. Yeah.
没事 没事
Just Nana's stuff.
这都是姥姥的东西
How we doing? You guys ready?
准备好出发了吗
Mom called to remind me not to wear my hair up.
老妈上午提醒我别把头发扎起来
Did you know my ears were not my best feature?
你们是不是也觉得我耳朵不太好看
Some days it's all I can think about.
那都是曾经了
Hi. I'm sorry I'm late. I couldn't find my bearings.
抱歉来晚了 我找不到我的'耳圈'了
Heh. You mean your earrings?
你是说耳环吧
What did I say?
我刚才说的是啥
-Are these the shoes? -Yes. Paolo sent them from Italy.
-就是这双鞋吗  -没错 保罗从意大利寄过来的
What? We, uh, don't have shoes here?
美国这边没有卖鞋的吗
Morning. We ready to go?
早上好 走吗
Don't we look nice all dressed up?
穿的都很漂亮嘛
It's stuff like that, isn't it?
就是因为这种事吧
-It was a beautiful service. -It really was.
-葬礼办的非常好  -是啊
Come here, sweetheart.
抱一个 亲爱的
You know...
对了
...I think it's time for you to start using night cream.
你这皮肤以后得用用晚霜了
What?
咋了
Nothing. Just your overcoat sounds remarkably like Brent Musburger.
没啥 突然发现你衣服说起话来跟播音员似的
Check it out. Giants-Cowboys.
牛仔对巨人
You're watching football at a funeral?
你居然在葬礼上看球赛
No, it's the pregame. I'm gonna watch it at the reception.
没有 正赛前准备呢 一会儿招待会上我再看
You're a frightening, frightening man.
你真是个奇男子
Oh, no. My new Paolo shoes.
噢 我的保罗鞋
Oh. I hope they're not ruined.
希望没破掉
God, what a great day.
今天的天可真好啊
What? Weatherwise.
我说的是天气
I know.
没错
The air, the trees.
空气好 树也发芽了
Even though Nana's gone, there's something almost, uh, life...
虽然姥姥走了 但还是有很多...
-Ross, are you okay? -Ross!
罗斯 没事吧
I'm fine. No, I'm fine.
没事 没事
Just...
就是
...having my worst fear realized, but...
好像噩梦成真的感觉
I'm just checking to see if the muscle's in spasm.
我给你看看是不是肌肉抽筋了
-Huh. -What? What is it?
-呀  -怎么了
You missed a belt loop.
丢了一个皮带环
Okay, it's in spasm.
没错 抽筋了
Here, sweetie. Here.
给你这个
I took these when I had my golfing accident.
我打高尔夫受伤的时候就用的这个
Thanks, Mom.
谢了 老妈
Sorry.
抱歉
Hi, I'm Andrea.
我叫安迪雅
I'm Dorothy's daughter.
多西的女儿
Hi, I'm Chandler, and I have no idea who Dorothy is.
我叫钱德 而且我完全不知道多西是哪位
Hey, look who's up.
快看谁来了
-Hey. -How do you feel?
-嘿  -感觉如何
I feel great.
棒呆了
I feel great. I feel great.
飞一般的感觉
Wow, those pills really worked, huh?
这些药还真管事啊
Yeah. Not the first two, but the second two, whew.
前两片还没事 不过后两片嘛
I love you guys.
我爱死你们了
You guys are the greatest. I love my sister.
你们最棒了 我爱我妹妹
I love Pheebs. Ha.
还有菲比
-That's so nice. -Hey.
-太贴心了 -嘿
Chandler.
钱德
I love you, man.
我爱你 老兄
And listen, if you wanna be gay, be gay.
听着 想当同志就尽情当吧
It doesn't matter to me.
我不在乎
You were right.
你猜对了
Rachel. Rachel, Rachel.
瑞秋 瑞秋
I love you the most.
我最爱你了
Well, you know who I love the most?
你知道我最爱谁吗
-No. -You.
-不知道  -你啊
Oh, you don't get it.
你没明白我的意思
-Aw! -What do you got there?
-靠  -你拿的是啥
Uh, just a, uh, hearing disability.
额 我耳朵不太好使 助听的
What's the score?
比分多少了
17-14, Giants. Three minutes to go in the third.
巨人领先3分 第三节还剩3分钟
Beautiful.
犀利啊
Pheebs, could you maybe hand me a cracker?
菲比 能帮我拿块饼干吗
Your grandmother would've hated this.
你姥姥一定不喜欢这样
Well, sure. What with it being her funeral and all.
肯定啊 毕竟这是她的葬礼
No, I'd be hearing about...
她肯定会不停的抱怨
...why didn't I get the honey-glazed ham?
怎么没给我买糖浆火腿啊
Or I didn't spend enough on flowers. If I spent more, she'd say:
责怪我花买少了 但是买多了她又会说
"Why waste your money? I don't need flowers, I'm dead."
'我都死了 买这么多花有意义吗'
That sounds like Nana.
听着挺像姥姥的风格
Do you know what it's like to grow up...
小时候和一个总是挑你毛病的人...
...with someone who is critical of every single thing you say?
生活在一起 你能明白这种感受吗
I can imagine.
我能想象
I tell you, it's a wonder your mother turned out...
就这样我还能成为一个...
...to be the positive, life-affirming person she is.
充满正能量的人 太罕见了
That is a wonder.
确实罕见
So tell me something, Mom. If you had to do it all over again...
那我问您一句 如果能重来
...I mean, if she was here right now...
我是说 如果姥姥在这
...would you tell her?
你会直接告诉她吗
Tell her what?
告诉她什么
How she drove you crazy, picking on every little detail.
就是无论你怎么做 她都会过分挑剔
Like your hair, for example.
比如说发型之类的
I'm not sure I know what you're getting at.
我不太明白你的意思
Would things have been better if you'd just told her the truth?
如果实话实说 会不会好一点
No.
未必
I think some things are better left unsaid.
我想有些事还是不说的好
I think it's nicer when people just get along.
随和一点挺好的
More wine, dear?
再喝点吗
Oh, I think so.
必须的
Those earrings look really lovely on you.
这对耳环真配你
Thank you.
谢谢
They're yours.
这是你的耳环
Actually, they were Nana's.
是你姥姥传下来的
No!
日
Now I'm depressed.
现在我真是伤心了
Even more than I was.
比之前还伤心
Hey, who's this little naked guy?
这个裸体小男孩是谁啊
Uh, that little naked guy would be me.
这个裸体小帅哥是我
Aw. Look at the little thing.
快看这个小东西
Yes, fine. That is my penis.
没错 那是我的小弟弟
Can we be grownups now?
能成熟点吗
-Who are those people? -Got me.
-这些人是谁啊  -不知道了
That's Nana right there in the middle.
中间那个是姥姥
Yeah, let's see.
我看看
"Me and the gang at Java Joe's."
'在咖啡店随手一拍'
Wow. Monica, you look just like your grandmother.
莫妮卡 你长得太像你姥姥了
How old was she there?
她那会儿多大
Let's see. "1939."
我看看 1939年
Uh, twenty-four, twenty-five.
24左右吧
Huh. It looks like a fun gang.
这群人看起来挺开心的
Ooh, look, look, look. I got Monica naked.
看这边 我找到裸体莫妮卡了
Let me see.
让我看看
No, no. That would be me again.
不是 这张还是我
I'm, uh, just trying something.
我当时正在...做试验
-Hey, Lowell. -Oh, hey, Chandler.
-嘿 洛尔  -嗨 钱德
So how's it going in Financial Services?
金融部的工作还忙吗
It's like Mardi Gras without the papier-mâché heads.
无聊得就像春节不放炮一样
How about you?
你呢
Good. Good. Listen, um, heh...
还不错 对了
...I don't know what Shelly told you about me, but, uh...
我不知道雪莉是怎么说我的 但是...
...I'm not.
我不是
I know. That's what I told her.
我知道 我也是这么告诉她的
-Really? -Yeah.
-是吗  -嗯
So you can tell?
你能看出来
Pretty much. Most of the time. We have a kind of radar.
多数时候都能 我们在这方面有天赋
So you don't think I have...
这么说你不认为我有...
...a quality?
这种特质了
Speaking for my people, I'd have to say no.
作为一个同性恋 我觉得没有
By the way, your friend Brian from Payroll?
对了 工资部的布莱恩...
He is.
他有
-He is?  -Yep.
-他是吗  -是
And way out of your league.
但是配你有点白瞎了
Out of my league.
我配不上他
I could get a Brian. If I wanted to get a Brian, I could get a Brian.
只要我想 搞定布莱恩还不是分分钟的事
Hey, Brian.
嘿 布莱恩